Contact

7272499912 (Mobile) norton.michele@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/michelenorton (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Performance Improvement Informatics Business Strategy

Languages English

Michele Norton, MS RN

Healthcare Executive | Clinical Outcomes | Population Health | Strategy | Healthcare Analytics & Technology | Engagement Tampa/St. Petersburg, Florida Area

Summary

Executive level healthcare professional experienced in clinical operations and engagement, product strategy, product management, product marketing, and product optimization, as well as joint business development and acquisitions, channel management, sales support and strategic marketing. In depth knowledge of multiple EHR, analytics and CDS solutions including clinical optimization, workflow, outcomes measurement and result dissemination. Experience with many facets of the healthcare industry including large health care systems, hospitals, health plans and PBMs, ACOs, and community based care transition programs. Demonstrated experience in developing, launching, optimizing, and selling clinical technology products, analytics solutions and Insights as a Service, evidence-based CDS solutions and services from concept inception through operational support.

Specialties: Clinical Informatics, Clinical Adoption and Engagement, Project and Product Management, Marketing, Sales Support, Clinical Workflow and Optimization. Industry Organizational leader- HIMSS, AHIP, AMIA, CHIMSS. Critical Care Nursing- Specialty in CVICU adults and pediatrics.

Experience

SCIO Health Analytics®
Senior Vice President Marketing, Analytics, Strategy
June 2015 - Present (5 years 2 months)

Zynx Health
Director Product Strategy and Marketing
November 2011 - May 2015 (3 years 7 months)

tampa/st. petersburg, florida area

Responsible for defining Zynx product solution offering, developing goto-market strategy, product positioning and value proposition, content to

Page 1 of 5

support market awareness, demand generation, pipeline development and sales enablement. Responsible for developing the strategy and execution of customer success, PR and thought leadership programs.

McKesson Corporation

Director, Strategic Programs- Marketing January 2009 - November 2011 (2 years 11 months)

Led the development and deployment of a unified market awareness and thought

leadership program for the Health Systems Enterprise Solutions business segment.

Managed thought leadership and CXO outreach budgets exceeding \$500,000 Developed PR strategy to promote customer success and gain industry recognition

through speaking engagements, industry and McKesson publications, industry award

programs and clinical leadership webinar series

Created and deployed net new Clinical Excellence Award Program Led development of expanded business partnerships with key industry organizations-

AONE, ACPE, NPSF, AMDIS, ISMP and AHA

Led the development and deployment of an annual joint Nursing and Physician Leadership Congress

Created and executed quarterly CPOE Open House and Illumination Forums

Managed strategic advisory councils- nursing, physician and CIO

Supervised and mentored marketing manager and associates

McKesson Provider Technologies

12 years 5 months

Director Clinical Marketing January 2006 - November 2011 (5 years 11 months)

Westminster CO

Responsible for developing selling tools, campaign generation, thought leadership and market awareness programs for the Horizon Clinical solution suite including nursing, physician and pharmacy product lines. Assist in formulating overarching clinical strategy and roadmaps, business development and product launch, trade show and industry analyst relationships and customer relations/communications.

Clinical Specialist- Sales Support

January 2004 - January 2006 (2 years 1 month)

Responsible for the pre- sales cycle and sales enablement for the Horizon Clinical product suite. Supported the clinical sales team in demonstrating the Horizon Clinical product suite benefits, workflow and integration through product education, development liaisons, system implementation and build and customer relationship assistance.

Senior Product Manager 2001 - January 2004 (3 years)

Responsible for product vision, requirement, scope documentation, business plans, pricing, packaging, coordination of marketing and sales education and collateral materials for multiple clinical product lines in the Horizon suite. Assisted with pilot site coordination for beta sites. Led client focus groups and advisory board panels for the Horizon Clinical product line. Worked closely with client c suite and project teams to successfully deploy and optimize clinical solutions.

Senior Clinical Analyst Product Development July 1999 - November 2001 (2 years 5 months)

Liaison between clients and technical development resources. Develop detailed use

cases, clinical workflows and requirements for new and existing clinical products. Led clinical focus groups and usability testing.

Senior Clinical Analyst

July 1999 - September 2001 (2 years 3 months)

Liaison between clients and technical development resources. Develop detailed use cases, clinical workflows and requirements for new and existing clinical products in the Horizon suite. Led focus groups and usability testing.

University of Colorado Health Sciences Center Adjunct Faculty- SON 2004 - 2010 (6 years)

Adjunct Facutly- UCHSC SON Nursing Informatics Masters Program

Solution Consultant Group Product Specialist March 2004 - December 2006 (2 years 10 months)

Responsible for the pre- sales cycle for the Horizon Clinical Product Suite. Supported the

clinical sales team in demonstrating the Horizon Clinical product suite benefits, workflow and integration through product education, development liaisons, system

implementation and build and customer relationship assistance.

Provider Technologies

Horizon Clinical Senior Product Manager November 2001 - March 2004 (2 years 5 months)

Responsible for product vision, requirement, scope documentation, business plans,

pricing, packaging, coordination of marketing and sales education and collateral

materials for multiple Clinical product lines. Assisted with pilot site coordination for

beta sites. Led client focus groups and advisory board panels for the Horizon Clinical

product line.

St. Joseph's Hospital

RN and preceptor

April 1998 - January 2000 (1 year 10 months)

RN and preceptor, 20 bed Surgical and Medical Intensive Care Unit

Olsten Health Services Staffing

Critical Care Program Director

July 1998 - July 1999 (1 year 1 month)

Administrator specializing in critical care recruitment, sales, product lines implementation, and critical care education.

Cross Country Staffing

Travel Nurse Employment

July 1996 - April 1998 (1 year 10 months)

Registered Nurse in ICU settings at the following facilities: UCLA Medical Center, Presbyterian Hospital, Memorial Mission Hospital, Fairfax Hospital, Florida Hospital and St. Joseph's Hospital. Specializing in adult and pediatric Cardiovascular ICU nursing.

Shands Teaching Hospital, University of Florida Staff Nurse

May 1995 - July 1996 (1 year 3 months)

, 18 bed CVICU specializing in cardiac and thoracic surgery and transplants

Education

University of Colorado Anschutz Medical Campus MS, Nursing Informatics · (2001 - 2004)

University of Colorado Denver Health Science Center Masters of Science, Nursing, Nursing Informatics Specialty 2004 · (2001 - 2004)

University of Florida BSN, Nursing · (1990 - 1995)

University of Florida, College of Nursing Bachelor of Science, Nursing · (1990 - 1995)